RG 009:007, Indian Litigation Files
Connecticut State Library
- Series 5. Mashantucket Pequot, 1800-2007; bulk 1982-2007
  - Maps, 1855-2007
    - E.P.A. Documents for Land Parcels
      - Assessor's tax map, Town of Ledyard, Connecticut, 1999 April 1; 1 map, photocopy (Box 81)
        The map was removed from Box 15 Folder 15, "Miscellaneous - deeds"
        Sheet 30 of 144 sheets
      - Assessor's tax map, Town of Ledyard, Connecticut, 2002 July 1; 1 map, photocopy (Box 81)
        Sheet 43 of 144 sheets
      - Assessor's tax map, Town of Ledyard, Connecticut, 1995 July 1; 2 duplicate maps, photocopy (Box 81)
        Sheet 44 of 144 sheets
      - Plan made for State of Connecticut showing the Reservations of the Eastern Pequot Tribe of Pequot Indians, Town of Ledyard, Connecticut, 1963 January; 1 map, photocopy; Chandler & Palmer Engineers, (Box 81)
        # 123
      - Property ownership & jurisdiction, Town of Ledyard, New London County, State of Connecticut, 2007 March 7; 1 map (Box 81)
        >Map created...by Paul Nichols, Ledyard Planning Department. Parcels and ownership date to May 2006. Some parcels have multiple layers of jurisdiction not noted here. Data compiled from Assessor records, Town Clerk cemetery reference book dated year 2000, Town Clerk map files, and Planning Department files. Map is for reference only. Data is not authoritative
      - Reservation...surveyed in the fall of 1855 under the...Committee Appointed to sell..., 1 map, photocopy (Box 81)
        # 103
      - Town of Ledyard Geographic Information System (GIS), 824R, 2007 November 13; 1 printed sheet, 8.5 x 11 in. (Box 81)
      - Map showing wetlands, archaeological sites & land parcels owned by the Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation, 2006 October 31; 1 map (Box 81)
        Created by Planning Department GIS Division… Sources: Ledyard Assessor maps, North Stonington Assessor maps, and Preston Assessor maps
      - Plan made for State of Connecticut showing the Reservations of the Eastern Pequot Tribe of Pequot Indians, Town of Ledyard, Connecticut, 1963 January; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies; Chandler & Palmer Engineers, (Box 81)
        The maps were removed from Box 15 Folder 15, "Miscellaneous - deeds"
      - Tribal settlement boundary defined by Public Law 98-134, circa 2005; 1 map, photocopy (Box 81)
        The map was removed from Box 15 Folder 32
        # 2438
- Series 6. Mohegan, 1848-2006; bulk 1981-2006
  - Legal Documents, circa 1981-1994
    - Pleadings and exhibits, circa 1981 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Response of Robert B. Cohen to Attorney Griner's communication to the court of June 16, 1994, 1994 June 28 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs, circa 1980-1990
    - Petition for Federal Recognition Submitted by the Mohegan Tribe to the United States Department of the Interior, volume 1-A, Narrative Statement Concerning Criteria Set Forth in 25 CFR 83.7(e), 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Respondent State of Connecticut Supplemental Brief Concerning Proposed Findings, United States Department of Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Submitted in Opposition to the Mohegan Petition for Federal Recognition, circa 1980-1990; 1 volume (Box 15)
  - E.P.A., 1848-2006; bulk 1994-2006
    - Clean Air Act, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence and memorandum - land acquisition, 1994-1999 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence and related documents, circa 1994-2006 (Box 15, Folder 53-54)
    - Deeds and additional material, 1848-2006; photocopies (Box 15, Folder 55-57)
    - Miscellaneous deeds and property descriptions, 1996-2005, undated; photocopies (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - Miscellaneous research materials, 1956-2005; photocopies (Box 15, Folder 59-60)
    - Miscellaneous research materials, 1942-2006; photocopies (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
    - Montville appeal, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Southeastern Connecticut Regional Resources Recovery Authority Access Easement Issue, 1996-2006 (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence, 1997
    - Correspondence - United States District Court District of Connecticut, 1997 May 27 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Subject Files, 1899-2006
    - Clippings, 1997-2006, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Commissioner of Indian Affairs re Mohegan & other NE Indians, 1899 July 10; photocopy (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Indians - Clean Air Act federal regulations, 1994-1998; photocopies (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Montville voting and other records, circa 1981-1990, undated (Box 16, Folder 13-14)
    - Solicitor's letter RE acknowledgment guidelines and reconsideration, circa 1934-1994, undated (Box 16, Folder 15-17)
    - Research materials from the Massachusetts Archives, undated; photocopies (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - TIP/TAS application, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Maps, 1981
    - Residential Property forms with maps, circa 1981; photocopies (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
    - E.P.A.
      Maps were removed from subseries E.P.A.
      - Property survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, CT. RTE 2A & Mohegan Sun Boulevard, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 November; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        The map was removed from Box 15 Folder 57
      - Monumented Property Survey Depicting Land to be Conveyed from Southeastern Connecticut Regional Resources Recovery Authority to the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, land lying north of Connecticut Route# 2A, Montville, Connecticut, 1995 September; 14 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        File # 1441
      - Perimeter Survey Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route No. 433 & Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        Identification Number: 1966
      - Perimeter Survey Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route No. 433 & Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 2 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
      - Property Survey Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 2A & Mohegan Sun Boulevard, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 November; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        File # 1564
      - Survey Plan showing Parcel for use of Replication of S.C.R.R.R.A. Lands. Off Sandy Desert Road, 1994 December; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        File # 1439
        Identification Number: 94-1798
      - Property Survey Prepared for MTIC LLC. Lands to be Conveyed to the Town of Montville, Connecticut, 1996 September 13; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        Job Number: 1967
      - Property/Easement Plan. Fort Hill, Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. 1710 Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 June 6; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        Project 1586.00
      - Property Survey Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut Depicting Lands of Edward G. & Beatrice L. Bernat and Lands of the State of Connecticut. Fort Shantok Road & Connecticut Route 2A, Montville, Connecticut, 1995 October; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        Identification Number: 95-1874
      - Town of Montville Map Showing Land & Easements to be Transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department, Thames River Bridge & Approaches (Limited Access Highway), 1965 March; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        Project Number: 85-75
        Sheet 1 of 5
      - Town of Montville Map Showing Land & Easements to be Transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department, Thames River Bridge & Approaches (Limited Access Highway), 1965 March; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        Sheet 2 of 5
      - Town of Montville Map Showing Land & Easements to be Transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department, Thames River Bridge & Approaches (Limited Access Highway), 1965 March; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        Sheet 4 of 5
      - Property Line Survey Prepared for: Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 September 15; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        Project 15713.00
      - Property Line Survey Prepared for: Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 September 15; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
      - Tax Map 49, Town of Montville, Connecticut, 2004 April 1; 4 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
      - Property Survey Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut Depicting Lands of Edward G. & Beatrice L. Bernat and Lands of the State of Connecticut. Fort Shantok Road & Connecticut Route 2A, Montville, Connecticut, 1995 October; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        Received for Record 2006 April 12
      - Property/Easement Plan. Fort Hill, Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. 1710 Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 June 6; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        Received for Record 2006 April 17
      - Property/Easement Plan. Fort Hill, Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. 1710 Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 June 6; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
      - Property Survey Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut Depicting Lands of Edward G. and Beatrice L. Bernat and Lands of the State of Connecticut. Fort Shantok Road and Connecticut Route # 2A, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 May; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        File# 1505
      - Survey Plan Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians (U.N.C., Inc. Property). Sandy Desert Road, Uncasville, Connecticut, 1994 December; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        File# 1440
        Identification Number: 94-1801
      - Property Survey prepared for MTIC LLC. Lands to be Conveyed to the Town of Montville. Montville, Connecticut, 1996 September 13; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        File# 1477
      - Property Survey prepared for MTIC LLC. Lands to be Conveyed to the Town of Montville. Montville, Connecticut, 1996 September 13; 4 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route # 2A and Mohegan Sun Boulevard, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 November; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        Job Number: 2003
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route # 2A and Mohegan Sun Boulevard, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 November; 1 map, photocopy (Box 82)
        File# 1564
      - Property/Easement Plan. Fort Hill, Mohegan Tribe of Indians Connecticut. 1710 Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 June 6; 4 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        Project 15586.00
      - Property/Easement Plan. Fort Hill, Mohegan Tribe of Indians Connecticut. 1710 Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 June 6; 4 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
      - Property Line Survey Prepared for: Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 September 15; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        File# 2070
        Project Number: 15713.00
      - Property Line Survey Prepared for: Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 September 15; 6 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        File# 2071
      - Survey Plan showing Parcel for use of Replication of S.C.R.R.R.A. Lands. Off Sandy Desert Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1994 December; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 82)
        File# 1439
      - Property Survey Prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut Depicting Lands of Edward G. and Beatrice L. Bernat and Lands of the State of Connecticut. Fort Shantok Road and Connecticut Route # 2A, Montville, Connecticut, 1995 October; 4 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department Thames River Bridge and Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 7 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
        Serial Number: 45
      - Town of Montville map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department Thames River Bridge and Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 7 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department Thames River Bridge and Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        Sheet 3 of 5
      - Town of Montville map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department Thames River Bridge and Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 2 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department Thames River Bridge and Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 3 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
        Sheet 5 of 5
      - Town of Montville map showing land transferred from the Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation. Fort Shantok / Connecticut Route Number 2A, 1994 December; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        File# 1406
        Project Number: MISC
        Serial Number: 104
      - Town of Montville map showing land transferred from the Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation. Fort Shantok / Connecticut Route Number 2A, 1994 December; 4 duplicate maps, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville map showing land transferred from the Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation, 1996 January; 3 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
        Project Number: 000
        Serial Number: 104A
      - Town of Montville map showing land transferred from the Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation, 1996 September 19; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        File# 1476
      - Perimeter Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route Number 433 and Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        File# 2072
      - Perimeter Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route Number 433 and Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Perimeter Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route Number 433 and Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        File# 2068
      - Perimeter Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route Number 433 and Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 5 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Easement to be acquired from the State of Connecticut (Fort Shantok State Park) in favor of S.C.R.R.R.A.. Fort Shantok Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1993 March 2; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        File# 1335
        Project: 86-571A
      - Plan prepared for S.C.R.R.R.A. showing a permanent easement through State of Connecticut land. Fort Shantok Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1989 November 15; 10 duplicate maps, photocopy (Box 83)
        Project: 86-571-A
      - Town of Montville map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department Thames River Bridge and Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 2 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Monumented Property Survey Depicting Land to be Conveyed from Southeastern Connecticut Regional Resources Recovery Authority to the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Land lying north of Connecticut Route# 2A, Montville, Connecticut, 1995 September; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        File# 1441
      - Plan and Profile prepared for MTIC, LLC. property to be conveyed to the Town of Montville, Topographic Survey, 1995 February 24; 2 maps, photocopies (Box 83)
        File# 1478
      - Tax Map 49 Town of Montville, Connecticut, 2004 April 1; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Environment Protection Agency submitted boundary maps by the Mohegan Tribe of Indians, 2005 September 22; 7 maps (Box 83)
        Folder contains:
        1. Ida McDowell, United States Environmental Protection Agency, memorandum to Daniel R. Schaefer, Esq. Subject: Mohegan Tribe of Indians Boundary Map. "Enclosed is a map of boundaries as submitted by the Mohegan Tribe of Indians in their request for eligibility determination and Clean Air Act program approval…"
        2. Geographic Information Systems - Planning, six maps.
      - Montville Map showing the location of a section of highway to be abandoned on Fort Shantok Road which shall revert to the town as per Section 2, Public Act 235, 1967 Session of the General Assembly, 1968 May 17; 2 duplicate maps, photocopies; Connecticut State Highway Department. (Box 83)
        Project 85-75
      - Unidentified road map, undated; 1 map, 11 x 17 in. (Box 83)
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route # 2A and Mohegan Sun Boulevard, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 November; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Property Line Survey prepared for: Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 September 15; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Perimeter Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route Number 433 & Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        The map was removed from Box 15 Folder 58
      - Tax Map 49, Town of Montville, Connecticut, 2004 April 1; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land transferred from the Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation. Fort Shantok/Connecticut Route Number 2A, 1994 December; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land transferred from the Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation, 1994 December; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        Serial Number: 104 A
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 2A & Mohegan Sun Boulevard, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 November; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        Project Number: 2003
      - Town of Montville Map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department, Thames River Bridge & Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Property Survey prepared for MTIC LLC. lands to be conveyed to the Town of Montville. Montville, Connecticut, 1996 September 13; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut depicting lands of Edward G. and Beatrice L. Bernat and lands of the State of Connecticut. Fort Shantok Road and Connecticut Route # 2A, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 May; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 2A & Mohegan Sun Boulevard, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 November; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Preliminary Property Line Survey prepared for: Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 32, Uncasville, Connecticut, 2000 September 15; 2 maps, photocopies (Box 83)
        Sheet 1 to 2
      - Survey Plan prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians (U.N.C., Inc. Property). Sandy Desert Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1994 December; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Perimeter Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, Fort Shantok State Park. Connecticut Route Number 433 & Massapeag Side Road, Montville, Connecticut, 1997 January; 2 maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 2A & Mohegan Sun Boulevard, 1997 November; 3 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department, Thames River Bridge & Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land transferred from Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation, 1996 January; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Unidentified map, undated; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Tax Map 49, Town of Montville, Connecticut, 2004 April 1; 2 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land transferred from Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation. Fort Shantok/Connecticut Route 2A, 1994 December; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department, Thames River Bridge & Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 2 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land transferred from Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation, 1996 January; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land transferred from Department of Environmental Protection to the Department of Transportation. Fort Shantok/Connecticut Route 2A, 1994 December; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
      - Town of Montville Map showing land & easements to be transferred from State Park & Forest Commission to the State Highway Department, Thames River Bridge & Approaches (limited access highway), 1965 March; 8 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Property Survey prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut. Connecticut Route 2A & Mohegan Sun Boulevard, 1997 November; 2 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Survey Plan prepared for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians (U.N.C., Inc. Property). Sandy Desert Road, Montville, Connecticut., 1994 December; 3 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
      - Plan and Profile prepared for MTIC, LLC. property to be conveyed to the Town of Montville. Topographic Survey, 1996 February 24; 8 duplicate maps, photocopies (Box 83)
    - Maps
      The following maps were removed from Box 16, Folder 20-21
      - Architectural building plans of the Mohegan Congregational Church building, 1991 April 22; 1 map, photocopy (Box 83)
        Montville Building Inspector Douglas Palmer, Building Office Certified Copy
      - Property Map, 55. Town of Montville, New London County, Connecticut, 1991 April 22; 1 map, photocopy; Prepared by James W. Sewall Company, Old Town, Maine. (Box 83)
        Assessor's Certified Copy
      - Property Map, 56. Town of Montville, New London County, Connecticut, 1991 April 22; 1 map, photocopy; Prepared by James W. Sewall Company, Old Town, Maine. (Box 83)
      - Property Map, 87. Town of Montville, New London County, Connecticut, 1991 April 22; 1 map, photocopy; Prepared by James W. Sewall Company, Old Town, Maine. (Box 83)
      - Property Map, 48. Town of Montville, New London County, Connecticut, 1991 April 22; 1 map, photocopy; Prepared by James W. Sewall Company, Old Town, Maine. (Box 83)
      - Property Map, 42. Town of Montville, New London County, Connecticut, 1991 April 22; 1 map, photocopy; Prepared by James W. Sewall Company, Old Town, Maine. (Box 83)
      - Property Map, 41. Town of Montville, New London County, Connecticut, 1991 April 22; 1 map, photocopy; Prepared by James W. Sewall Company, Old Town, Maine. (Box 83)